ARUN KUMAR RAMASAMY

20 Panton street, Cambridge, UK | <u>arun.k.rams@gmail.com</u> UK: +44 (0)7539065445/India: +91 (0)9704333549

www.linkedin.com/in/arunkrams



SUMMARY

Certified Agile Product Owner/Business Analyst professional with high regards to ethical values, integrity and compliance. Accomplished senior professional with 15+ years of experience across the product life cycle, owning and delivering technical solutions to industry challenges by combining technical prowess with effective leadership to drive successful outcomes.. An empathetic team leader provided business process consulting for utilities in India (NPCL: ~0.1M consumers) & Malaysia (TNB: ~10M consumers) and collaborated with stakeholders across Engineering, Product Management, Sales and Services, Partners and Customer organizations of varied scales worldwide.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Agile Product Owner / Business Analyst

Senior TPM | GE Digital, Cambridge, UK | Sep 2020 - Nov 2023 (3 years 3 months) TPM | GE Power, Hyderabad, India | Feb 2013 - Jan 2015 (2 years)

- Strengthened the geospatial solutions for utility asset management by enhancing modeling capability and interoperability: from defining the goals/ requirements to delivering MVP 100% on time quarterly.
- Spearheaded the agile scrum teams: defined and groomed the release/sprint backlog with DoR qualified user stories along with customer usage scenarios, in line with the mid-term (3-6 months) & long-term (1-3 years)) strategic plans for native interoperability enabling modular COTS SaaS offerings.
- Guided the scrum teams with sprint goals & planning, engaged with product architects and technical leads for solution design & implementation, and test cases with QA for acceptance tests(DoD) with 100% test coverage.
- Re-engineered business process for customer workflows as well as for Engineering teams, owners of developing solutions worth ~\$1M effort every quarter addressing the inputs from teams gathered in release retros.
- Provided insights into scrum team KPI data, with risks/mitigation strategies to stakeholders, and influenced the pivot with technical approach and resource allocation to deliver 100% customer operable solution.
- Managed the partner ecosystem from incubation to operation and support by acting as a single point of contact on a
 transitory basis and ensured quality deliverables. Contributed to the organization-wide engineering initiatives towards
 quality and customer issue resolution, improving it by ~80%.
- Driven the customer acceptance of the product solutions and prioritized the customer feedback as product backlog and delivered 30% within the release and 70% future product roadmap.

Senior Consultant

RedPlanet Group, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia | Apr 2016 - Aug 2020 (4 years 5 months) Hexamap Solutions, Greater Noida, India | Feb 2015 - Mar 2016 (1 year 2 months)

- Upgraded GIS solution to end-users with high customer value and realized pipeline for enhancements & new projects generating additional revenue of ~1M MYR.
- Accomplished business goals across the project lifecycle: User requirements gathering, Business process design and solution implementation, Project Management, L1/L2 M&S Project Lead and Stakeholder Management with 100% OTD.
- Acted as SME in Business Process Modelling with customers, guided the change management team with valuable inputs for defining the 'To Be' business processes for 5 business divisions

ARUN KUMAR RAMASAMY

20 Panton street, Cambridge, UK | arun.k.rams@gmail.com UK: +44 (0)7539065445/India: +91 (0)9704333549

www.linkedin.com/in/arunkrams



- Utilized agile methodology techniques and delivered solutions to end users in a phased manner from 1 or 2-year cycle to 3-month and on-demand cycles, resulting in better revenue recognition and growth.
- Driven the 100% provisional acceptance of the delivered solution and provided training to end users.
- Improved the customer issue resolution, change request and solution development processes and progressed towards 0% downtime as part of M&S activities.
- Contributed to the customer base expansion: technical pre-sales pitch with the Sales team during initial customer engagement, prepared technical proposals responding to 10+ RFPs and networked using industry conferences.

Product Developer & Quality Analyst

GE Power, Jun 2008 - Jan 2013 (4 years 8 months)

- Demonstrated agility swarming across developer and QA activities and played a pivotal role in designing solutions for the specific areas: upgrades, data model, usability & performance; demonstrated an excellent grasp of domain and functionality in arriving at a robust 'right 1st time' design for the solutions in a prompt way.
- Developed an in-house tool for the Project Quality management team to track and measure 100% OTD metrics.
- Accomplished QA ensured the quality of product, functional and non-functional aspects and automated 80 key customer business processes thereby eliminating manual effort.

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

- GE Innovator Award: Recognition for the successful submission of the following invention disclosure: "Integrated Review Feedback System for GIS Applications"
- GE Innovator Award: Recognition for successful submission of invention disclosure: Power System Equipment On-line Monitoring And Diagnostics Using Spectroscopy.
- IMPACT Award Deliver with Focus: Recognized for ensuring 100% OTD of 'planned' features to meet customer commitments despite budget and recruitment challenges for the past three years
- IMPACT Award Expertise: Recognition for the expert guidance to the team, which won the ERD award.
- Best Volunteer Award for volunteer activities in engagement with GE Volunteers.
- GE Spotlight awards for exemplary performance on project deliverables.

SKILLSET

- Business Process Re-engineering
- Requirements Engineering
- Technical Solution Design
- Stakeholder Engagement
- Multicultural Team Leadership
- Technology Solution Delivery
- **Continuous Improvement**
 - **Customer Value**
- **Analytical Skills**
- Data Analysis & Governance
- **Technical Consulting**

- Magik C#.Net Python Web technologies | Agile Scrum / Kanban Waterfall SDLC TDD BDD
- Aha! JIRA Confluence AzureDevOps Rally Assembla MIRO Mixpanel PowerBI Tableau GitHub

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Scrum Product Owner [CSPO], Scrum
- Aha! Academy Product Management Aha!.
- Product Analytics Micro-certification, Product School.
- Certified 'Green Belt' [DFSS & DMAIC-Lean] by GE

EDUCATION

- Master of Science in Psychology, TamilNadu Open University, Chennai
- Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics & Instrumentation, Madras Institute of Technology, Anna University, Chennai